thank you
[Music]
suppose we have a right triangle and off
each of the legs we have a semicircle
with diameter equal to the leg of the
triangle
furthermore imagine a semi-circle that
has a diameter along the hypotenuse
according to the Pythagorean theorem the
area of the large semicircle on the
hypotenuse equals the sum of the areas
of the other two semicircles
so in this picture the Blue Area
counteracts the yellow area now when we
reflect the semicircle on the hypotenuse
about the hypotenuse and cancel the blue
and yellow areas of overlap we see that
the right triangle is filled and we've
created two loons off of the legs of the
right triangle like this
but from the Pythagorean theorem we know
that the blue shaded area and the yellow
shaded area are still equal
this means that the combined area of the
two loons constructed on the legs of a
given right triangle must be equal to
the area of that right triangle
this is a theorem due to Hippocrates of
chios
[Music]